Another specific we need to know before doing our genetic algorithms'
在讲遗传算法之前 我们还要知道一点
example is that there are 28 possible pairs of attacking queens
共有 28 对可能相互攻击的女皇
on this eight by eight board.
待在这个 8 乘 8 的棋盘上
&gt;&gt; How did you figure that out?
你怎么知道的？
&gt;&gt; Well, we have eight queens, and
我们有 8 个女皇
we want to examine every possible pair that could attack each other.
而我们想研究每对可能攻击彼此的女皇
So that has eight choose two or
所以是八选二种可能性
8 factorial over 8 minus 2 factorial times 2 factorial.
那就是 8! / (8 - 2)! * 2!
&gt;&gt; That's good to know, since our goal with n queens is to reduce
很好 由于 n 皇后的目标是
the number of attacking pairs of queens to zero.
把皇后攻击对减少到 0
We're going to find a fitness function for
所以我们要为棋局找一个适应度函数
a board to be the maximum number of attacking pairs of queens, which is 28,
函数应为皇后攻击对的最大值 也就是 28
minus the number of attacking queens for a given board.
减去给定棋局的攻击皇后数
In the case of eight queens, when the fitness function reaches 28,
在八皇后中 适应度函数等于 28
we'll know we've won.
我们就赢了
Genetic algorithms is an analogy to natural selection in biology.
遗传算法类比了生物学里的自然选择
It uses breeding and mutation to find the optimal answer to a problem.
使用繁衍和变异的思路来为问题求最佳解
I think it's best to explain Genetic Algorithms with an example.
我觉得最好在讲遗传算法时举些例子
Okay, then let's welcome the eight queens problem.
好 那欢迎八皇后问题登场
To get thing started, let's choose four random boards.
首先 我们随机选四个棋局
These four boards represent our gene pool, and
这四个棋局代表我们的基因库
we're going to try a breed better boards by combining them in different patterns.
我们要试着让它们以不同的方式结合 从而繁衍出更好的棋局
&gt;&gt; How do we choose which ones to use?
我们要怎么选呢？
&gt;&gt; Easy, survival of fittest.
容易 适者生存
We'll evaluate each board according to the fitness function we just described.
根据刚才讲的适应度函数来评估各棋局
The top board only had four attacking pairs,
最上面的棋局只有 4 个攻击对
which means it had a score of 28 minus 4 or 24.
也就意味着其适应度函数的值为 28 - 4 也就是 24
The next one had five attacking pairs, so its score is 23.
下一个有 5 个攻击对 所以值为 23
The remaining two have scores of 20 and 11, respectively.
剩下的两个值分别为 20 和 11
&gt;&gt; Poor number 4.
可怜的第四个
He will probably never get to have kids.
可能永远都没机会生小孩了
Evolution can be cruel.
进化真残酷
[MUSIC]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; Anyway, from these fitness scores, we will create proportional probabilities
不管怎么说 我们根据适应度的值 按比例生成概率
for how likely each one is to breed.
从而确定各棋局繁衍的概率有多大
&gt;&gt; So basically, we're going to add the four scores and
所以基本上我们就是把四个值相加
normalize each one into a percentage.
然后将各值转化为分数
&gt;&gt; Yep.
对的
&gt;&gt; Okay, so 24 plus 23 plus 20 plus 11 is equal to 78.
好 所以 24 + 23 + 20 + 11 等于 78
And, 24/78=31%.
24/78 = 31%
So, our most fit board has a 31% chance to be chosen as a parent.
所以适应度最高的棋局有 31% 的概率被选为父代
&gt;&gt; That's right.
对的
We'll continue to calculate these percentages for each board and
继续计算各棋局的百分比
we get 29%, 26%, and 14%.
得到 29%、26% 和 14%
&gt;&gt; Poor number four.
可怜的第四个
&gt;&gt; Would you stop it?
你能别玩了吗？
&gt;&gt; [SOUND] &gt;&gt; Okay,
— [声音] — 好了
now we're going to select four parents to create four new children.
现在我们选出四个父代来生成四个子代
To do that we basically roll a 100 sided die to select the first parent.
选择过程大概就是投掷一颗有 100 面的骰子 选出第一个父代
If it is 1 to 31, we select the first board.
如果掷出的点数在 1 - 31 之间 那就选第一个棋局
And if 32 to 60, the second, and so on.
如果在 32 - 60 之间 那就选第二局 以此类推
Say we roll a 55, so for the first parent, we get the second board.
假设我们掷出了 55 因此第一个父代选第二局
&gt;&gt; And we roll the 100 sided die again, and for the second parent,
再次投掷那个 100 面的骰子 得到第二个父代
I get the first board.
是第一个棋局
&gt;&gt; And we continue this process.
继续这个步骤
The third parent will be the second board.
第三个父代是第二个棋局
&gt;&gt; Lucky board.
真幸运
&gt;&gt; And for the last parent, we get the third board.
最后一个父代是第三个棋局
&gt;&gt; Poor- &gt;&gt; Don't say it.
— 可怜的… — 别说了！
&gt;&gt; Okay, so for these lucky boards, they are going to produce offspring.
好了 这些幸运的棋局会开始繁衍后代
How many children will we produce for each set of parents?
每对要繁衍多少子代呢？
&gt;&gt; Two.
两个
&gt;&gt; Is there any reason for that?
为什么呢？
&gt;&gt; Well with genetic algorithms, there are many parameters we can change to
用遗传算法时 我们有很多参数可以修改
try to optimize how quickly we converge to a good result.
我们可以尽量最优化 以便尽快收敛 获得令人满意的解
Let's stick with two here for convenience.
为了方便 就假设这里会繁衍两个子代吧
&gt;&gt; Okay, so now that we know which parents we have and
好的 现在我们知道父代是什么
how many children we will produce, how do we make children?
也知道要繁衍多少子代了 那要怎么繁衍呢？
&gt;&gt; That's a process we call crossover.
繁衍过程叫交叉
You see we've selected a point along each pair of parents.
你可以看到每对父代都选了些位置
We pick this point randomly and
随机选的
then we create the first child by taking the first part of the first parent and
把第一个父代的第一部分
then tack that on to the last part of the second parent.
与第二个父代的第二部分重组 就生成了第一个子代
This process sounds more like assembling Frankenstein's monster from body parts
这听着更像是弗兰肯斯坦用身体的不同部分拼凑怪物
than breeding, but okay.
而不像繁衍 不过你接着说吧
&gt;&gt; Then for the second child we take the first part of the second parent and
要生成第二个子代 我们取第二个父代的第一部分
add it to the last part of the first parent.
与第一个父代的第二部分重组
We do the same process with the second set of parents here.
对第二对父代进行同样的操作
&gt;&gt; It's alive.
它活过来了！
&gt;&gt; [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; So hopefully in
— [笑声] — 所以
at least one of the children, we get the best attributes of the parents.
希望至少有一个子代能得到父代的最优特性
It kind of reminds me of the movie Twins with Arnold Schwarzenegger and
这让我想起了电影 《龙兄鼠弟》里的阿诺·斯瓦辛格
Danny DeVito.
和丹尼·德维托
&gt;&gt; You're showing your age, I wasn't born yet when that movie came out.
你暴露年龄了 那部电影放映的时候我还没出生
&gt;&gt; Still, it was a good movie.
但那仍不失为一部好电影
&gt;&gt; But I actually had a point, what if, like in the supposition in the movie,
不过我知道你想说什么了 如果像电影假想的一样
one child gets all the good aspects of the parents and
有个子代继承了父代的全部优点
the other one gets all the bad aspects?
另一个子代却继承了全部缺点怎么办？
&gt;&gt; Well, then in the next generation, the one with less attacking queens will
那么在下一代里 皇后攻击对更少的子代
have a higher fitness function and have a higher chance to create children.
适应度函数值会更高 因而更有机会繁衍子代
And the one with more attacking queens will have a lower fitness function and
皇后攻击对较多的子代则适应度函数值较低
less chance to create children.
繁衍子代的概率也就比较低
&gt;&gt; And we hope that by having enough generations, we will eventually evolve
我们希望在繁衍出足够多的代数后 可以进化出
an eight queens gameboard that solves the problem.
一个解了问题的八皇后棋局
&gt;&gt; There's one more critical step, but
还有至关重要的一步
first let's review crossover more carefully.
但我们先来好好回顾下交叉的过程